worldremit.com 2016-10-26

# WorldRemit Privacy Policy

## Australia

Effective 18 November 2014

**WorldRemit Pty Ltd - Australia Privacy Policy**

WorldRemit Pty Ltd (ABN 23 154 871 011) ('WorldRemit', 'we', 'us') is a subsidiary of WorldRemit Ltd.

At WorldRemit we are committed to ensuring the privacy of the personal information you have provided us. We are bound by the Australian Privacy Principles ('APPs') established under the Privacy Act 1998 (the 'Act'), which require you to be informed about how we handle your personal information. This Privacy Policy ('Privacy') describes how WorldRemit collects, holds, uses and discloses your personal information and how the information is protected.

All third parties (including customers, suppliers, sub-contractors, and agents) that have access to or use personal information collected and held by us must abide by this Policy.

Copies of this Policy are available free of charge by contacting our Privacy Officer or can be downloaded from our website www.worldremit.com. _Please note that, this Policy does not extend to websites of third parties that we may provide links to on or from our website._

In this Policy:

  * 'Disclosing' information means providing information to persons outside of us;
  * 'Personal information' means information or an opinion relating to an individual, which can be used to identify that individual;
  * 'Privacy Officer' means the contact person for questions or complaints regarding our handling of personal information;
  * 'Sensitive information' is personal information that includes information relating to a person's racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religion, trade union or other professional or trade association membership, sexual preferences and criminal record, and also includes health and biometric information; and
  * 'Use' of information means our use of information.

#### Type of personal information we collect

We collect and hold a range of personal information including:

  * Your identity particulars, including your full name, residential address, date of birth, gender, contact details, and details of specific primary identification documents e.g. Drivers Licence, Passport or Medicare Card numbers.
  * Any additional personal information you provide to WorldRemit online, by email, telephone or other correspondence;
  * Your Occupation;
  * Your Payment details;
  * Transaction information;
  * Biometric information (only for the purposes of verifying your identity); and
  * Demographic information such as age, gender and post code.
  * Details of services or products you acquire from WorldRemit or you enquire about, along with any additional information that may be necessary to deliver the requested WorldRemit products and services to you.

_Sensitive personal information_

We will not collect sensitive information about you without your consent unless an exemption in the APPs applies. These exceptions include if the collection is required or authorised by law or necessary to take appropriate action in relation to suspected unlawful activity or serious misconduct. For example, we might collect your biometric information when confirming your identity.

#### How we collect the information

We generally collect your personal information:

  * When you complete the WorldRemit online registration form when you request/submit an online money transfer request or airtime service through your WorldRemit online account.
  * From information disclosed to us by you on the phone, or by sending us correspondence (including letters, faxes and emails) or visiting us in person;
  * From a variety of third party sources, including our business contacts, identity verification service providers, financial institutions,
  * Directly from applications, questionnaires and other forms you may complete when you wish to use our services.

In some circumstances we may be provided with personal information about you from a third party. If so, we will take reasonable steps to inform you that we hold the personal information and the purpose for which we hold the personal information. We will take reasonable steps to make you aware of this Policy.

Please note that you do not have the option of dealing with us anonymously, or by using a pseudonym. This is because it is illegal for us to deal with individuals who are not identified.

_If you do not provide us with the personal information we request, we may not be able to provide you with our products or services, or process your application to access our products or services, process your funds transfer request._

#### Unsolicited personal information

We may receive personal information about you when we have taken no active steps to collect that information. This is known as 'unsolicited' personal information. We destroy or de-identify all unsolicited personal information we receive, unless it is relevant to our purposes for collecting personal information. We may retain additional information we receive about you if it is combined with other information we are required or entitled to collect. If we do this, we will retain the information in the same way we hold your other personal information.

#### Use of your personal information

We may use and disclose your personal information for any of the purposes mentioned below. We may also use and disclose your personal information for secondary purposes which are related to the primary purposes set out above, or in other circumstances authorised by the Privacy Act. Sensitive information will be used and disclosed only for the purpose for which it was provided (or a directly related secondary purpose), unless you agree otherwise or an exemption in the Act applies.

At WorldRemit we use and disclose the information collected and held about you so that we may:

  * Provide you with the WorldRemit service you have requested, enquired, ordered through our website www.worldremit.com (including money transfers, airtime top up and other product and services as made available by us);
  * Fulfil your order, send your order confirmation and to manage our customer service communications with you;
  * Verify your identity in order to provide you with the product(s) or service(s) you have requested;
  * Comply with our various regulatory and legal obligations including but not limited to the Anti-Money Laundering and Counter Terrorism Financing Act 2006 (Cth);
  * Further improve and develop our products and services;
  * Determine whether you came to our website from a banner ad or an affiliate website;
  * Ascertain and establish effective marketing campaigns;
  * Provide you with information about WorldRemit products and services;
  * Consider and investigate any concerns or complaints you may have; and
  * Continuously improve our website and our customer experiences.

#### Disclosure of your personal information and sending information overseas

We disclose your personal information to:

  * Our related entities, including our operating Headquarters WorldRemit Ltd in the United Kingdom and our affiliate office in the USA;
  * Our correspondent partners, disbursement and payment provider partners for the purposes of processing your requested transaction;
  * The Identification Verification agencies used to confirm your identity and meet the applicable identification and verification regulatory requirements;
  * Our digital marketing/advertising analysts and providers for email marketing and consumer choice and data analysis;
  * To government agencies, law enforcement bodies and courts where required by law;
  * To third parties as permitted and required law; and
  * Anyone to whom you authorise us to disclose to.

Information disclosed to third parties will only be information required for the supply and fulfilment of the WorldRemit product and service, or for customer assistance purposes or as required by law. Strict confidentiality agreements will be adhered to by the respective receiving third party. We are likely to disclose your information to third parties located in Australia, USA, UK and Europe.

WorldRemit is committed to the protection of your information and only deal with ethical suppliers and business partners who demonstrate similar values and are bound by privacy laws of the same standard as Australia.

We will not disclose your personal information to overseas recipients without your consent unless:

  * We have taken reasonable steps to ensure that the recipient does not breach the Privacy Act, or the APPs; or
  * The recipient is subject to a similar information privacy regime.

#### Storage and security of your personal information

When we collect personal information from you, we follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information collected by us, both during transmission and once we receive it. We will take all reasonable steps to protect your personal information from loss, misuse and interference, and unauthorised access, modification and disclosure. We endeavour to maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect your personal information. We also endeavour to restrict access to your personal information by our employees and third parties to information they reasonably require.

We understand our customers require peace of mind when it comes to information security. We use modern security measures such as secure firewalls, servers, databases and data encryption to safeguard the personal information provided by you. Furthermore, hard copies data files are filed in secured cabinets and only accessible to the designated employee. And if no longer required disposed of securely through the available secured bins.

We will retain your information for as long as needed to provide services to you, or as required by law. Where we no longer need your information, we will take reasonable steps to destroy or de-identify it.

Despite our efforts, no method of transmission over the internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. If you have any questions about security on our website, please contact us.

#### Direct marketing

We may use your personal information to send you direct marketing material. We will only use personal information we collect from you for the purposes of direct marketing without your consent if:

  * the personal information does not include sensitive information; and
  * you would reasonably expect us to use or disclose the information for the purpose of direct marketing; and
  * we provide a simple way of opting out of direct marketing; and
  * you have not requested to opt out of receiving direct marketing from us.

We do not disclose personal information we collect to others for the purpose of allowing them to direct market their products and services. We do not use or disclose sensitive information for direct marketing purposes.

If we collect personal information about you from a third party, we will only use that information for the purposes of direct marketing if you have consented (or it is impracticable to obtain your consent), and we will provide a simple means by which you can easily request not to receive direct marketing communications from us. We will draw your attention to the fact you may make such a request in our direct marketing communications.

You have the right to request us not to use or disclose your personal information for the purposes of direct marketing, or for the purposes of facilitating direct marketing by other organisations. We must give effect to the request within a reasonable period of time. You may also request that we provide you with the source of their information. If such a request is made, we must notify you of the source of the information free of charge within a reasonable period of time. You may choose to stop receiving marketing emails by either:

  * clicking on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the WorldRemit advertising/promotional materials;
  * by sending us an email to [customerservice@worldremit.com](mailto:customerservice@worldremit.com)
  * using this form

#### Quality of your personal information

We are committed to ensuring that the personal information we collect, hold, use and disclose is relevant, accurate, complete and up-to-date.

Before we use or disclose your information, we will take reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information is accurate, complete, relevant, up-to-date and is not misleading. We encourage you to regularly review your personal information and update your personal information in your WorldRemit profile.

We encourage you to contact us if any personal information we hold about you needs to be updated. If we correct information that has previously been disclosed to another entity, we will take reasonable steps notify the other entity of the correction. Where we are satisfied information is inaccurate, we will take reasonable steps to correct the information within 30 days, unless you agree otherwise. We will not charge you for correcting your personal information.

#### Access to your personal information

Subject to the exceptions in the Privacy Act, you can access the personal information that we hold about you by contacting the Privacy Officer. We will generally provide you with the requested information within 30 days of request. In the event that we are unable to do so or not required by law to do so, we will inform you of the reasons for refusal.

We will require evidence that the request is coming from you and specification of what information is required. An administrative fee for searches, collation of information, photocopying costs may apply. To request information stored about you, contact us:

  * By email: [privacy@worldremit.com](mailto:privacy@worldremit.com)
  * By mail: To the Privacy Officer, WorldRemity Pty Ltd, Level 16, 1-7 Castlereagh Street, Sydney NSW 2560

We will endeavour to grant you access to personal information which we hold about you within 30days of receiving your request.

#### How to make a privacy complaint?

WorldRemit takes all complaints seriously and will investigate your complaint accordingly.

If you believe that there has been a breach of the Australian Privacy Principles or elements of this Privacy Policy, or if you have any concerns about WorldRemit's handling of your personal information, please contact us using the Contact Us tab on our website or by emailing us at [privacy@worldremit.com](mailto:privacy@worldremit.com) or by calling our Customer Service Help Desk on 02 6145 2161. Your Privacy Complaint must be directed and addressed to the Privacy Officer.

Please note that we aim to respond complaints within 30days of receipt. If you are not satisfied with our response to your complaint, you can also refer your complaint to the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner by:

  * Telephoning the OAIC on 1300 363 992
  * Writing to the OAIC - Director of Complaints, Office of the Australian Information Commissioner, GPO Box 5218, Sydney NSW 2001.
  * Emailing the OAIC - [enquiries@oaic.gov.au](mailto:enquiries@oaic.gov.au)

#### Cookies & internet technology

We may use cookies, for example, to keep track of your preferences and profile information. Cookies are also used to collect general usage and volume statistical information that does not include personal information.

Third party data technologies are used within the WorldRemit app by WorldRemit Ltd and our marketing partners. These technologies are used to monitor app usage and track in-app events, and information from these technologies may be reported on both an individual and aggregate basis.

**Full terms and conditions can be found on our website. Accordingly, usage of the website assumes acceptance of theseterms and conditions.**

_Web beacons_

Our website contains electronic images known as 'Web Beacons' (sometimes called single-pixel gifs). These are used along with cookies to compile aggregated statistics to analyse how our site is used and may be used in some of our emails to let us know which emails and links have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of our customer communications and marketing campaigns.

We use a third party to gather information about how you and others use our website. For example, we will know how many users access a specific page and which links they clicked on. We use this aggregated to understand and optimize how our website is used.

You should be aware that any information you provide in these blogs and forums may be read, collected and used by others who access them.

#### Changes to this policy

We may update this Policy to reflect changes to our information handling practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on our website prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

#### Contact information

You can contact us about this Privacy Policy by writing or email us at the address below:

  * By Email: [privacy@worldremit.com](mailto:privacy@worldremit.com)
  * By Phone: +61 (02) 6145 2161
  * By Mail: WorldRemit Pty Ltd, Level 16, 1-7 Castlereagh Street Sydney NSW 2000

## Canada

**Effective November 27, 2015**

This privacy policy applies to WorldRemit Inc. The use of personal information in Canada is protected by the _Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act_ (PIPEDA) and Canada’s anti-spam legislation

**"Personal Information"** refers to information that can be used to identify an individual.

WorldRemit Inc. is committed to respecting and protecting your privacy. We value you as a client and want you to understand how we collect, use, protect, and disclose information about you. Please read the privacy policy carefully.

**When do we collect information?**

  * when you visit our website to register
  * when you conduct a transaction
  * when you are contacted by phone, e-mail or SMS requesting additional information.

**What Information do we collect?**

Personal information we may collect can include:

  * Contact information such as name, address, telephone number, e-mail address. In addition to this we also ask for your gender and date of birth.
  * Payment details in order to process the transaction (banking or credit card information)
  * A valid government issued identification (such as passport, driver’s license)
  * Beneficiary information such as name, address, mobile number e-mail address.
  * Banking details of the recipient if this option is available in the receive country.
  * Information that we indirectly obtain from you, such as information about the device, hardware and software you use when accessing the Service, your IP address, the pages you access on this website, and other websites that you visit prior to accessing the Service.
  * Recordings of your communications with our Customer Service department, including telephone calls and electronic communications. This information may also be used for training purposes.
  * Any additional information requested by staff such as occupation
  * Any additional personal information you provide to WorldRemit online, by e-mail or telephone.

**Your personal information may be disclosed to:**

  * Related entities which would include our headquarters located in the United Kingdom and any of our affiliate offices.
  * The Identification Verification agencies used to confirm your identity and meet the applicable identification and verification regulatory requirements;
  * Agents for the purposes of completing the transaction. In order to complete a transaction, we may on occasion need to provide additional information
  * Canadian regulators and Law enforcement in order to meet regulatory requirements
  * Marketing in order to ascertain and establish effective promotional, marketing campaigns. You may choose to stop receiving electronic marketing messages we send my clicking on the unsubscribe button

**Do we use 'cookies'?**

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site's or service provider's systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

**We use cookies to:**

  * Help remember and process your transactions
  * Understand and save user's preferences for future visits.
  * Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third party services that track this information on our behalf.

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser's Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

If you disable cookies off, you will not be able to conduct a transaction.

**Third party links**

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

Third party data technologies are used within the WorldRemit app by WorldRemit Ltd and our marketing partners. These technologies are used to monitor app usage and track in-app events, and information from these technologies may be reported on both an individual and aggregate basis.

**How do we protect visitor information?**

Our website is scanned on a regular basis for security holes and known vulnerabilities in order to make your visit to our site as safe as possible.

We implement a variety of security measures when a user places an order enters, submits, or accesses their information.

Please take note that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. We therefore, cannot guarantee its absolute security.

**Changes to this policy**

We may amend this Policy at any time. If any material changes are made in the manner in which we collect, use or store your information, we will notify you by email or by means of a notice on our website prior to the change becoming effective. This website will contain the most current privacy policy therefore we encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

**How to contact us:**

If there are any questions or concerns about this policy, you can contact us using the information below.

Worldremit.com

1000 Rue de la Gauchetiere Ouest

Suite 2400

Montreal, Quebec, H3B 4W5

+1-514-448-7496

## Japan

Effective on 12/11/2015 .

WorldRemit Ltd is registered as a data controller with the UK Information Commissioner’s Office with a registration number 07110878. This privacy policy describes how WorldRemit Ltd collects and uses your personal information, including the information you provide on the website:www.worldremit.com, owned and operated by WorldRemit Ltd (“we”, “us” or “our”) or our mobile application. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information

If you have questions or concerns regarding this policy, you should first contact us using this form.

WorldRemit Ltd has received TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this website, www.worldremit.com and does not cover information that may be collected through our mobile application.

In order to view our relationship with TRUSTe please visit the validation page visible by clicking on the TRUSTe seal. If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe here

**Collection and Use of Personal Information**

We collect the following personal information from you

• Contact information such as name, title, email address, mailing address, phone number

• Evidence of your identity (for example passport information)

  * Information about your social media profiles made available to us from your interactions with us on social media sites such as Facebook or Twitter

• Unique Identifiers such as user name, account number, password

• Billing information such as a credit card number and billing address

• Date of birth

• Demographic information such as age, education, gender, interests and zip code

We use this information to

• Register you with an account

• Provide the Services as described in our terms and conditions

• Fulfill your Transaction/ (Airtime Top Up) Request

• Send you a confirmation

• Send you requested service information

• Improve your online experience and our website/ service

• Comply with our legal and regulatory obligations

We also maintain records of your transactions and card and bank details where appropriate.

**Choice/Opt-Out**

You may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails or you can contact us using this form.

We will also send you service related email announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. You do not have an option to opt out of these emails, which are not promotional in nature.

**Information Obtained about Third Parties**

You may provide us with personal information about others, such as Recipients’ name and identifiers, address, phone number, bank account details or email address. If so, you confirm that you have appropriate authority to do so and to allow us to use that information and we will only use it for the specific reason for which it was provided to us.

**Information Sharing**

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy or the terms and conditions, such as credit reference agencies to verify your identity or Recipients of the money transferred through the Service. We may share your information with certain third parties who we believe may be of interest to you where we have your consent to do so.

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities or offering customer service such as local banks or money exchange houses or IT or digital marketing providers. These companies are authorised to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services. If in any doubt, please contact us.

We may also disclose your personal information

• as required by law such as to comply with a court order, subpoena, or similar legal process,

• when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, fulfil our legal or compliance obligations, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a governmental or regulatory request,

• if WorldRemit Ltd is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information,

• to any other third party with your prior consent to do so.

We may transfer your personal information overseas and to jurisdictions which may offer a level of legal protection to your information which does not meet European legal standards. In such cases, we take steps to protect your information and only make such transfers in compliance with the Data Protection Act 1998.

**Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies**

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by WorldRemit Ltd and our marketing partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the website, tracking users’ movements around the website and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We use cookies to remember users’ settings, for authentication and for enhanced user experience. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our website, but your ability to use some features or areas of our website may be limited. Please see our Cookies Policy for further information and how to opt out.

  * **Log Files**

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve services we offer you and site functionality.

  * **Local Storage Objects (HTML 5)**

We use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 to store preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our website or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity also use LSOs such as HTML 5. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs.

  * **Behavioral Targeting / Re-Targeting**

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by [clicking here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). You will continue to receive generic ads.

**Links to Other Web Sites**

Our Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of WorldRemit Ltd. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Web site you visit.

**Security**

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter certain information such as a credit card number on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using reasonable security measures. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our website, you can contact us at this form.

**Social Media Widgets**

Our website includes Social Media Widgets or Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Twitter button which are interactive mini-programs that run on our site to provide specific services from another company (e.g. displaying the news, opinions, music, etc). Personal information, such as your email address, may be collected through the Widget. Cookies may also be set by the Widget to enable it to function properly. Information collected by this Widget is governed by the privacy policy of the company that created it.

**Testimonials**

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our website in addition to other endorsements, where you have agreed with a third party review site that we may do so. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at this form.

**Correcting and Updating Your Personal Information**

You may request to review, delete or update your personal information to ensure it is accurate, by contacting us at this form. We aim to respond to your request for access within 30 days.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services, including a record of your Transactions on our website. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at this form. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements and will securely delete your information when we no longer have a need to retain it.

**Notification of Privacy Policy Changes**

We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this website or via a link from your mobile application prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

**Contact Information**

You can contact us about this privacy policy by writing or email us at the address below:

WorldRemit Ltd. 

Japan

Ark Mori Building 12F

1-12-32 Akasaka, Minato-ku

Tokyo 107-6012

Email: this form

Phone: +81-3-4588-8160

## New Zealand Privacy Policy

Effective 15 April 2015

**WorldRemit (New Zealand) Limited - New Zealand Privacy Policy**

WorldRemit (New Zealand) Limited _(Company No: 4705359 and a Registered financial services provider under the Financial Services Providers (Registration & Dispute Resolution) Act 2008 – FSP422206) _is a subsidiary of WorldRemit Ltd, the parent company _(registered in the UK under Company Registration number: 0711087, authorised and regulated by the Financial Conduct Authority (FCA) under the Payment Service Regulations 2009 for the provision of payment services; Registration number: 574642)._ 'WorldRemit', 'we', 'us')

At WorldRemit we are committed to ensuring the privacy of the personal information you have provided us. We are bound by the New Zealand Privacy Principles established under the Privacy Act 1993 (the 'Act'), which require you to be informed about how we handle your personal information. This Privacy Policy ('Privacy') describes how WorldRemit collects, holds, uses and discloses your personal information and how the information is protected.

All third parties (including customers, suppliers, sub-contractors, and agents) that have access to or use personal information collected and held by us must abide by this Policy.

Copies of this Policy are available free of charge by contacting our Privacy Officer or can be downloaded from our website www.worldremit.com. _Please note that, this Policy does not extend to websites of third parties that we may provide links to on or from our website._

In this Policy:

  * 'Disclosing' information means providing information to persons outside of us;
  * 'Personal information' means information or an opinion relating to an individual, which can be used to identify that individual;
  * 'Privacy Officer' means the contact person for questions or complaints regarding our handling of personal information;
  * 'Sensitive information' is personal information that includes information relating to a person's racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religion, trade union or other professional or trade association membership, sexual preferences and criminal record, and also includes health and biometric information; and
  * 'Use' of information means our use of information.

**Type of personal information we collect**

We collect and hold a range of personal information including:

  * Your identity particulars, including your full name, residential address, date of birth, gender, contact details, and details of specific primary identification documents for example Passport, Driver’s Licence etc.
  * Any additional personal information you provide to WorldRemit online, by email, telephone or other correspondence;
  * Your Occupation;
  * Your Payment details;
  * Transaction information;
  * Biometric information (only for the purposes of verifying your identity); and
  * Demographic information such as age, gender and post code.
  * Details of services or products you acquire from WorldRemit or you enquire about, along with any additional information that may be necessary to deliver the requested WorldRemit products and services to you.

_Sensitive personal information_

We will not collect sensitive information about you without your consent unless an exemption in the APPs applies. These exceptions include if the collection is required or authorised by law or necessary to take appropriate action in relation to suspected unlawful activity or serious misconduct. For example, we might collect your biometric information when confirming your identity.

**How we collect the information**

We generally collect your personal information:

  * When you complete the WorldRemit online registration form when you request/submit an online money transfer request or airtime service through your WorldRemit online account.
  * From information disclosed to us by you on the phone, or by sending us correspondence (including letters, faxes and emails) or visiting us in person;
  * From a variety of third party sources, including our business contacts, identity verification service providers, financial institutions;
  * Directly from applications, questionnaires and other forms you may complete when you wish to use our services.

In some circumstances we may be provided with personal information about you from a third party. If so, we will take reasonable steps to inform you that we hold the personal information and the purpose for which we hold the personal information. We will take reasonable steps to make you aware of this Policy.

Please note that you do not have the option of dealing with us anonymously, or by using a pseudonym. This is because it is illegal for us to deal with individuals who are not identified.

**_If you do not provide us with the personal information we request, we may not be able to provide you with our products or services, or process your application to access our products or services, process your funds transfer request._**

**Unsolicited personal information**

We may receive personal information about you when we have taken no active steps to collect that information. This is known as 'unsolicited' personal information. We destroy or de-identify all unsolicited personal information we receive, unless it is relevant to our purposes for collecting personal information. We may retain additional information we receive about you if it is combined with other information we are required or entitled to collect. If we do this, we will retain the information in the same way we hold your other personal information.

**Use of your personal information**

We may use and disclose your personal information for any of the purposes mentioned below. We may also use and disclose your personal information for secondary purposes which are related to the primary purposes set out above, or in other circumstances authorised by the Privacy Act. Sensitive information will be used and disclosed only for the purpose for which it was provided (or a directly related secondary purpose), unless you agree otherwise or an exemption in the Act applies.

At WorldRemit we use and disclose the information collected and held about you so that we may:

  * Provide you with the WorldRemit service you have requested, enquired, ordered through our website www.worldremit.com _(including money transfers, airtime top up and other product and services as made available by us);_
  * Fulfil your order, send your order confirmation and to manage our customer service communications with you;
  * Verify your identity in order to provide you with the product(s) or service(s) you have requested;
  * Comply with our various regulatory and legal obligations including but not limited to the Anti-Money Laundering and Countering Financing of Terrorism Act 2009;
  * Further improve and develop our products and services;
  * Determine whether you came to our website from a banner ad or an affiliate website;
  * Ascertain and establish effective marketing campaigns;
  * Provide you with information about WorldRemit products and services;
  * Consider and investigate any concerns or complaints you may have; and
  * Continuously improve our website and our customer experiences.

**Disclosure of your personal information and sending information overseas**

We disclose your personal information to:

  * Our related entities, including our operating Headquarters WorldRemit Ltd in the United Kingdom and our affiliate office in Australia and the USA;
  * Our correspondent partners, disbursement and payment provider partners for the purposes of processing your requested transaction;
  * The Identification Verification agencies used to confirm your identity and meet the applicable identification and verification regulatory requirements;
  * Our digital marketing/advertising analysts and providers for email marketing and consumer choice and data analysis;
  * To government agencies, law enforcement bodies and courts where required by law;
  * To third parties as permitted and required law; and
  * Anyone to whom you authorise us to disclose to.

Information disclosed to third parties will only be information required for the supply and fulfilment of the WorldRemit product and service, or for customer assistance purposes or as required by law. Strict confidentiality agreements will be adhered to by the respective receiving third party. We are likely to disclose your information to third parties located in New Zealand, Australia USA, UK and Europe.

WorldRemit is committed to the protection of your information and only deal with ethical suppliers and business partners who demonstrate similar values and are bound by privacy laws of the same standard as New Zealand.

We will not disclose your personal information to overseas recipients without your consent unless:

  * We have taken reasonable steps to ensure that the recipient does not breach the Privacy Act, or the Privacy Principles; or
  * The recipient is subject to a similar information privacy regime.

**Storage and security of your personal information**

When we collect personal information from you, we follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information collected by us, both during transmission and once we receive it. We will take all reasonable steps to protect your personal information from loss, misuse and interference, and unauthorised access, modification and disclosure. We endeavour to maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect your personal information. We also endeavour to restrict access to your personal information by our employees and third parties to information they reasonably require.

We understand our customers require peace of mind when it comes to information security. We use modern security measures such as secure firewalls, servers, databases and data encryption to safeguard the personal information provided by you. Furthermore, hard copies data files are filed in secured cabinets and only accessible to the designated employee. And if no longer required disposed of securely through the available secured bins.

We will retain your information for as long as needed to provide services to you, or as required by law. Where we no longer need your information, we will take reasonable steps to destroy or de-identify it.

Despite our efforts, no method of transmission over the internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. If you have any questions about security on our website, please contact us.

**Direct marketing**

We may use your personal information to send you direct marketing material. We will only use personal information we collect from you for the purposes of direct marketing without your consent if:

  * the personal information does not include sensitive information; and
  * you would reasonably expect us to use or disclose the information for the purpose of direct marketing; and
  * we provide a simple way of opting out of direct marketing; and
  * you have not requested to opt out of receiving direct marketing from us.

We do not disclose personal information we collect to others for the purpose of allowing them to direct market their products and services. We do not use or disclose sensitive information for direct marketing purposes.

If we collect personal information about you from a third party, we will only use that information for the purposes of direct marketing if you have consented (or it is impracticable to obtain your consent), and we will provide a simple means by which you can easily request not to receive direct marketing communications from us. We will draw your attention to the fact you may make such a request in our direct marketing communications.

You have the right to request us not to use or disclose your personal information for the purposes of direct marketing, or for the purposes of facilitating direct marketing by other organisations. We must give effect to the request within a reasonable period of time. You may also request that we provide you with the source of their information. If such a request is made, we must notify you of the source of the information free of charge within a reasonable period of time. You may choose to stop receiving marketing emails by either:

  * clicking on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the WorldRemit advertising/promotional materials;
  * by sending us an email to [customerservice@worldremit.com](mailto:customerservice@worldremit.com)
  * using this form

**Quality of your personal information**

We are committed to ensuring that the personal information we collect, hold, use and disclose is relevant, accurate, complete and up-to-date. Before we use or disclose your information, we will take reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information is accurate, complete, relevant, up-to-date and is not misleading. We encourage you to regularly review your personal information and update your personal information in your WorldRemit profile.

We encourage you to contact us if any personal information we hold about you needs to be updated. If we correct information that has previously been disclosed to another entity, we will take reasonable steps notify the other entity of the correction. Where we are satisfied information is inaccurate, we will take reasonable steps to correct the information within 30 days, unless you agree otherwise. We will not charge you for correcting your personal information.

**Access to your personal information**

Subject to the exceptions in the Privacy Act, you can access the personal information that we hold about you by contacting the Privacy Officer. We will generally provide you with the requested information within 30 days of request. In the event that we are unable to do so or not required by law to do so, we will inform you of the reasons for refusal.

We will require evidence that the request is coming from you and specification of what information is required. An administrative fee for searches, collation of information, photocopying costs may apply. To request information stored about you, contact us:

  * By email: [privacy@worldremit.com](mailto:privacy@worldremit.com)
  * By mail: To the Privacy Officer, WorldRemit (New Zealand) Limited

WorldRemit (New Zealand) Limited, 41 Shortland Street Plaza Level, Auckland, New Zealand 1010

We will endeavour to grant you access to personal information which we hold about you within 30 days of receiving your request.

**How to make a privacy complaint?**

WorldRemit takes all complaints seriously and will investigate your complaint accordingly.

If you believe that there has been a breach of the New Zealand Privacy Principles or elements of this Privacy Policy, or if you have any concerns about WorldRemit's handling of your personal information, please contact us using the Contact Us tab on our website or by emailing us at [privacy@worldremit.com](mailto:privacy@worldremit.com) or by calling our Customer Service Help Desk on +64 (09) 887 1710. Your Privacy Complaint must be directed and addressed to the Privacy Officer.

We will acknowledge receipt of your complaint within 2 business days. We will investigate your complaint and come back to you with the results of our investigation no later than 7 business days of receipt of your complaint. If you are not satisfied with the manner in which we have dealt with your complaint, or the outcome/resolution, then you may refer the matter to the Financial Dispute Resolution Scheme

By Mail: Level 9, 109 Featherston Street Wellington 6011 

By Phone: 0508 337 337

By Email: [enquiries@fdrs.org.nz](mailto:enquiries@fdrs.org.nz)

Online: <http://www.fdr.org.nz/making-complaint/make-complaint>

**Cookies & internet technology**

We may use cookies, for example, to keep track of your preferences and profile information. Cookies are also used to collect general usage and volume statistical information that does not include personal information.

Third party data technologies are used within the WorldRemit app by WorldRemit Ltd and our marketing partners. These technologies are used to monitor app usage and track in-app events, and information from these technologies may be reported on both an individual and aggregate basis.

**Full terms and conditions can be found on our website. Accordingly, usage of the website assumes acceptance of these** **terms and conditions** **.**

_Web beacons_

Our website contains electronic images known as 'Web Beacons' (sometimes called single-pixel gifs). These are used along with cookies to compile aggregated statistics to analyse how our site is used and may be used in some of our emails to let us know which emails and links have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of our customer communications and marketing campaigns.

We use a third party to gather information about how you and others use our website. For example, we will know how many users access a specific page and which links they clicked on. We use this aggregated to understand and optimize how our website is used.

You should be aware that any information you provide in these blogs and forums may be read, collected and used by others who access them.

**Changes to this policy**

We may update this Policy to reflect changes to our information handling practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on our website prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

**Contact information**

You can contact us about this Privacy Policy by writing or email us at the address below:

  * By Email: [privacy@worldremit.com](mailto:privacy@worldremit.com)
  * By Phone: +64 (09) 887 1710
  * By Mail: WorldRemit (New Zealand) Limited, 41 Shortland Street Plaza Level, Auckland, New Zealand 1010

## United States

Last Edited on – 12/11/2015

This privacy policy of WorldRemit Corp (“WorldRemit”, “We”, “Us”, “Our”), a Delaware corporation, effective on 12/11/2015 has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their 'Personally Identifiable Information' (PII) is being used online (online includes also our mobile applications). PII, as used in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.

The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this website, www.worldremit.com and does not cover information that may be collected through our mobile application.

In order to view our relationship with TRUSTe please visit the validation page visible by clicking on the TRUSTe seal. If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>

**What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our website or app?**

We may collect the following information about you, which may include non-public information:

• When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your full name, gender, age, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number, date of birth, social security number, bank account number, and credit or debit card information. This is required information to process your transaction and to help you with your experience;

• To facilitate our Service, we request certain third party personal information from you or your mobile devices address book, such as your recipient's full name, physical address, email address, and telephone number. We may also collect from you the recipient's sensitive financial information including bank account and routing numbers;

• Information about your usage of the Service, including your transaction history, how you use the Service to send or receive money, and to whom you send money;

• Information that we lawfully obtain from third parties, such as identity verification services, electronic database services, and credit reporting agencies; and

• Information that we indirectly obtain from you, such as information about the device, hardware and software you use when accessing the Service, your IP address, the pages you access on this website, and other websites that you visit prior to accessing the Service.

• Recordings of your communications with our Customer Service department, including telephone calls and electronic communications.

• Any additional personal information you provide to WorldRemit online, by e-mail or telephone.

You may provide us with personal information about others, such as Recipients’ name and identifiers, address, phone number, bank account details or email address. If so, you confirm that you have appropriate authority to do so and to allow us to use that information and we will only use it for the specific reason for which it was provided to us.

**When do we collect information?**

We collect information from you when you register on our site, place an order, or enter information on our online site or through customer service.

**How do we share and use your information?**

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy.

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as settlement of funds. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

We may use the information we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:

• To provide you with the WorldRemit Service you have requested, enquired, ordered through our website www.worldremit.com (including money transfers, airtime, and other products and services);

• To fulfill your order, send your order confirmation and to manage our customer service communications with you;

• To contact you by telephone using auto-dialed or pre-recorded message calls or text (SMS) messages (if applicable) as authorized for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy;

• To quickly process your transactions;

• To verify your identity;

• To collect payment for your use of the Service;

• To allow our partners to fulfill their obligations to you;

• To troubleshoot problems with the Service;

• To comply with applicable laws, regulations, and rules, such as those relating to "know-your-customer", and anti-money laundering requirements;

• To detect and prevent fraud and other illegal uses of the Service;

• To help us further improve and develop our products and services;

• To determine whether you came to our site from a banner ad or an affiliate website;

• To ascertain and establish effective promotional, marketing campaigns;

• To provide you with information about WorldRemit products and services that are most relevant for you; and

• To continuously improve our website and the customer experience at www.worldremit.com.

You may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page, or you can contact us at [CustomerService@WorldRemit.com](mailto:CustomerService@WorldRemit.com).

We may also disclose your personal information as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, bankruptcy proceedings, or similar legal process when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request.

If WorldRemit is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website, of any change in ownership, uses of your personal information, and choices you may have regarding your personal information. We may also disclose your personal information to any other third party with your prior consent.

**How can customers access their account?**

If you wish to request access of your personal information, please contact us at [CustomerService@WorldRemit.com](mailto:CustomerService@WorldRemit.com). We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**How do we protect visitor information?**

Our website is scanned on a regular basis for security holes and known vulnerabilities in order to make your visit to our site as safe as possible.

We implement a variety of reasonable security measures when a user places an order enters, submits, or accesses their information.

No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

**Do we use 'cookies' and other tracking technologies?**

We, affiliates, or analytics or service providers, use technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags, and scripts, to analyze trends, administer the website, tracking users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

**We use cookies to:**

• Help remember and process your transactions;

• Understand and save user's preferences for future visits;

• Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third party services that track this information on our behalf.

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser's Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

If you disable cookies, you will not be able to conduct a transaction.

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We do link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this website and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests.

We use Local Shared Objects, such as HTML5, to store preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our website or to display advertising based upon your web browsing activity also use HTML5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5.

**Third party links**

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

Third party data technologies are used within the WorldRemit app by WorldRemit Ltd and our marketing partners. These technologies are used to monitor app usage and track in-app events, and information from these technologies may be reported on both an individual and aggregate basis.

**California Online Privacy Protection Act**

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy.

**According to CalOPPA we agree to the following:**

Users can visit our site anonymously.

Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page, or as a minimum on the first significant page after entering our website.

Our Privacy Policy link includes the word 'Privacy', and can be easily be found on the page specified above.

We use Local Shared Objects, such as HTML5, to store preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our website or to display advertising based upon your web browsing activity also use HTML5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5.

**Third party links**

Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes:

• On our Privacy Policy Page.

Users are able to change their personal information:

• By calling us.

**How does our site handle do-not-track signals?**

We currently do not recognize "do-not-track" signals from your browser. We engage third parties, such as marketing or analytics partners, who may collect information about your online activities over time and across different websites when you use our websites.

**Does our site allow third party behavioral tracking?**

It's also important to note that we do not allow third party behavioral tracking.

**COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)**

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation’s consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children’s privacy and safety online.

We do not specifically market to children under 13.

**Social Media Widgets**

Our website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button, and Widgets, such as the Share This button or interactive mini-programs that run on our website. These Features may collect your Internet protocol address, which page you are visiting on our website, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our website. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy statement of the company providing it.

**Changes to this Policy**

We may amend this policy at any time, and shall notify you by posting a revised version on our website. Should we make a material change to the manner in which we collect, use or store your personal information, we shall provide prior notice on our website, or by email.

**Texas Residents:**

If you have a complaint, first contact the consumer assistance division of WorldRemit Corp at 1-888-961-4869, if you still have an unresolved complaint regarding the company's money transmission or currency exchange activity, please direct your complaint to: Texas Department of Banking, 2601 North Lamar Boulevard, Austin, Texas 78705, 1-877-276-5554 (toll free), [www.dob.texas.gov](http://www.dob.texas.gov/).

**Colorado Residents:**

If you have a complaint regarding the company’s money transmission or currency exchange activity, please direct your complaint to: State of Colorado, Department of Regulatory Agencies, Division of Banking, 1560 Broadway, Suite 975, Denver, Colorado, 80202; 303-894-7575; Email: [DORA_BankingWebsite@state.co.us](mailto:DORA_BankingWebsite@state.co.us) . Information on how to file a complaint, the complaint process, and complaint form, are available on the DORA/Division of Banking website:[ www.dora.colorado.gov](http://www.dora.colorado.gov/).

**Arkansas Residents:**

If you have a complaint, first contact the consumer assistance division of WorldRemit Corp. at 888-961-4869. If you still have an unresolved complaint regarding the company’s money transmission activity, please direct your complaint to the Arkansas Securities Department, 201 East Markham Street, Little Rock, Arkansas, 72201-1692. The telephone number is 501-324-9260 and the website is: [www.securities.arkansas.gov](http://www.securities.arkansas.gov/).

**Maryland Residents:**

If you have a complaint regarding the company’s money transmission activity, The Commissioner of Financial Regulation for the State of Maryland will accept all questions or complaints from Maryland residents regarding the licensee, WorldRemit Corp., license number 1179663, and control number 4700741, at Commissioner of Financial Regulation, Attention: Consumer Services Unit, 500 North Calvert Street, Room 402, Baltimore, Maryland, 21202, or by fax number: 410-333-3866, or by telephone at 410-230-6077 or 888-784-0136.

**Contacting Us**

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below.

worldremit.com 

600 17th Street,

Suite 200 S

Denver CO 80202

USA

+1-888-961-4869

## All other countries

Effective on 12/11/2015

WorldRemit Ltd is registered as a data controller with the UK Information Commissioner’s Office with a registration number 07110878. This privacy policy describes how WorldRemit Ltd collects and uses your personal information, including the information you provide on the website:www.worldremit.com, owned and operated by WorldRemit Ltd (“we”, “us” or “our”) or our mobile application. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this policy, you should first contact us using this form.

WorldRemit Ltd has received TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this website, www.worldremit.com and does not cover information that may be collected through our mobile application.

In order to view our relationship with TRUSTe please visit the validation page visible by clicking on the TRUSTe seal. If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe here

**Collection and Use of Personal Information**

We collect the following personal information from you

• Contact information such as name, title, email address, mailing address, phone number

• Evidence of your identity (for example passport information)

  * Information about your social media profiles made available to us from your interactions with us on social media sites such as Facebook or Twitter

• Unique Identifiers such as user name, account number, password

• Billing information such as a credit card number and billing address

• Date of birth

• Demographic information such as age, education, gender, interests and zip code

We use this information to

• Register you with an account

• Provide the Services as described in our terms and conditions

• Fulfill your Transaction/ (Airtime Top Up) Request

• Send you a confirmation

• Send you requested service information

• Improve your online experience and our website/ service

• Comply with our legal and regulatory obligations

We also maintain records of your transactions and card and bank details where appropriate.

**Choice/Opt-Out**

You may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails or you can contact us using this form.

We will also send you service related email announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. You do not have an option to opt out of these emails, which are not promotional in nature.

**Information Obtained about Third Parties**

You may provide us with personal information about others, such as Recipients’ name and identifiers, address, phone number, bank account details or email address. If so, you confirm that you have appropriate authority to do so and to allow us to use that information and we will only use it for the specific reason for which it was provided to us.

**Information Sharing**

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy or the terms and conditions, such as credit reference agencies to verify your identity or Recipients of the money transferred through the Service. We may share your information with certain third parties who we believe may be of interest to you where we have your consent to do so.

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities or offering customer service such as local banks or money exchange houses or IT or digital marketing providers. These companies are authorised to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services. If in any doubt, please contact us.

We may also disclose your personal information

• as required by law such as to comply with a court order, subpoena, or similar legal process,

• when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, fulfil our legal or compliance obligations, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a governmental or regulatory request,

• if WorldRemit Ltd is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information,

• to any other third party with your prior consent to do so.

We may transfer your personal information overseas and to jurisdictions which may offer a level of legal protection to your information which does not meet European legal standards. In such cases, we take steps to protect your information and only make such transfers in compliance with the Data Protection Act 1998.

**Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies**

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by WorldRemit Ltd and our marketing partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the website, tracking users’ movements around the website and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We use cookies to remember users’ settings, for authentication and for enhanced user experience. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our website, but your ability to use some features or areas of our website may be limited. Please see our Cookies Policy for further information and how to opt out.

  * **Log Files**

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve services we offer you and site functionality.

  * **Local Storage Objects (HTML 5)**

We use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 to store preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our website or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity also use LSOs such as HTML 5. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs.

  * **Behavioral Targeting / Re-Targeting**

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by [clicking here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). You will continue to receive generic ads.

**Links to Other Web Sites**

Our Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of WorldRemit Ltd. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Web site you visit.

**Security**

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter certain information such as a credit card number on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using reasonable security measures. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our website, you can contact us at this form.

**Social Media Widgets**

Our website includes Social Media Widgets or Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Twitter button which are interactive mini-programs that run on our site to provide specific services from another company (e.g. displaying the news, opinions, music, etc). Personal information, such as your email address, may be collected through the Widget. Cookies may also be set by the Widget to enable it to function properly. Information collected by this Widget is governed by the privacy policy of the company that created it.

**Testimonials**

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our website in addition to other endorsements, where you have agreed with a third party review site that we may do so. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at this form.

**Correcting and Updating Your Personal Information**

You may request to review, delete or update your personal information to ensure it is accurate, by contacting us at this form. We aim to respond to your request for access within 30 days.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services, including a record of your Transactions on our website. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at this form. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements and will securely delete your information when we no longer have a need to retain it.

**Notification of Privacy Policy Changes**

We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this website or via a link from your mobile application prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

**Contact Information**

You can contact us about this privacy policy by writing or email us at the address below:

WorldRemit Ltd

62 Buckingham Gate

London, SW1E 6AJ

United Kingdom

Email: this form

Phone: +44 (0)20 7148 5800
